# Bhumika Mittal

■ mittalbhumika7@gmail.com | mittalbhumika7 | ↑ bhumikamittal7 | ♦ bhumikamittal.in

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests include **cryptography** and **computational complexity**, with a focus on lattice-based cryptography. In particular, I am working on the fine-grained complexity of lattice problems and pre-image samplable trapdoor functions. I am also interested in quantum cryptography and quantum computing.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ashoka University Sonipat, India

Diploma in Advanced Studies and Research, Computer Science

2024 - Present

Thesis: Threshold Pre-Image Samplable Trapdoor Functions

Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computer Science; CGPA: 3.90/4.00

2021 - 2024

Minors in Mathematics, and Entrepreneurial Leadership & Strategy

# Relevant Coursework

Lattice-based Cryptography, SAT Solvers, Computer Security and Privacy, Elliptic Curves and Cryptography, Quantum Computing, Investigation of Dilithium, Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies, Theory of Computation

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

IIT Delhi New Delhi, India

Research Assistant

Sept 2024 - Present

- Designing a scalable reduction from the Closest Vector Problem to Weighted Max-SAT for even norms
- Implementing the reduction using the RC2 MaxSAT solver to evaluate its scalability and efficiency

#### Max Planck Institute for Software Systems

Saarbrücken, Germany

Visiting Research Fellow

May 2024 - Aug 2024

- Proposed the PACT metric for evaluating phase-concurrent execution efficiency
- Benchmarked various data structures for diverse graph workloads like analytics, traversals, and pattern matching
- Designed a system to efficiently handle a wide range of heterogeneous graph workloads, achieving improved throughput and performance

#### Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, DRDO

New Delhi, India

Research Intern

Nov 2023 – May 2024

- Designed an indigenous lattice-based post-quantum public key encryption and signature scheme
- Implemented constant-time code in C and deployed it in internal software
- Conducted a study on NIST PQC finalists, contributing to the security framework against algebraic attacks

# IIT Gandhinagar Research Assistant

Gandhinagar, India

May 2023 - Sept 2023

- Built a tool to model data flow in computation graphs for memory hierarchy evaluation
- Analyzed the transformer architecture (BERT) to identify hardware-level operations for efficient inference
- Proposed an architecture to reduce power consumption; used Timeloop-Accelergy for energy and latency estimates

#### Publications

#### Vortex: Efficient Adaptive Graph Store

 $in\ progress$ 

Seemant Achari, Bhumika Mittal, Ashvin Goel, Laurent Bindschaedler

# Energy-Efficient Accelerator Design for Language Models for Edge Computing

Philosophical Transactions A

Tom Glint, **Bhumika Mittal**, Santripta Sharma, Abdul Ronak, Abhinav Goud, Neerja Kasture, Zaqi Momin, Aravind Krishna, Joycee Mekie

On the Existence of Balanced Generalized de Bruijn Sequences

Discrete Mathematics Journal

Matthew Baker, **Bhumika Mittal**, Haran Mouli, Eric Tang

Link to paper

# Honors and Awards

- 2024 Summa Cum Laude, Ashoka University
- 2024 Silver Medalist, Department of Computer Science, Ashoka University
- 2024 Builder's Award for Service Excellence, Department of Computer Science, Ashoka University
- 2022 Undergraduate Research Excellence Award, Department of Mathematics, Ashoka University
- 2021-24 **Dean's List** (every semester), Ashoka University

# OTHER EXPERIENCES

Ashoka University Sonipat, India

7 × Teaching Assistant

Aug 2022 - May 2024

- Teaching Assistant for multiple courses like Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics (student feedback: 4.88/5)
- Facilitated the Science Communication module at the Lodha Genius Program for 200+ high school students

Lehigh University

Bethlehem, US

Exchange Student

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Consulted for Global Good Fund, establishing metrics to evaluate ESG impact, measure non-monetary outcomes
- Strategized optimal investment approaches to enhance ESG goals and ensure measurable financial outcomes

Plaksha University

Mohali, India

Instructor

April 2023 - June 2023

• Taught a Microcontrollers course to 200+ high school students through IoT projects using ESP32 chipset

• Designed a game development module, building 5 mathematical and hardware games for hands-on learning

WebVeda Remote

Tech and Product Manager

Feb 2021 - April 2022

- Ideated and developed the platform, scaling to 300k learners and generating \$1M revenue within 10 months
- Managed tech infrastructure, including payment gateways, email integration, and other critical components

# OTHER ACTIVITIES

# Mathematics for post-quantum cryptanalysis

Eötvös Loránd University

Student Participant - Selected with a Full Grant

August 2024

#### Undergrad Architecture Mentoring Workshop (uArch)

ISCA 2024, Argentina

Selected with a Full Grant

July 2024

# Summer Research Institute on Systems, Security, and Privacy

Participant

July 2024

**EPFL** 

## Workshop on Lattice-based Post-quantum Cryptography

Speaker, Co-organiser

Ashoka University

April 2024

# Academic Affairs Board

Computer Science Student Representative

Ashoka University

May 2023 – May 2024

#### IEEE Ashoka Student Branch

Director of Technology

Ashoka University

Computer Science Society

Aug 2023 – May 2024

Student Advisor, President

Ashoka University

Aug 2022 – May 2024

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C/C++, Solidity, Assembly, SML, HTML

Technologies: Qiskit, Hyperledger Fabric, Git, LATEX, Docker, SageMath

Other: Arduino Uno, ESP32, Raspberry Pi Pico